When working with documents, there may be
some information that you wish to display
consistently throughout the documents.
So if you had 20 pages, you may want
to have the date and the company logo
on every page and also page numbers.
To do that, you would use the headers
and footers section of the document.
Now the headers and footers
aren't displayed by default.
You have to actually access
them to enter the information.
So to do that, as you can see,
I have a blank document on the
screen, and there are two ways of
accessing the headers and footers.
You can go to the insert tab which
brings up the insert tool bar and
then select header and footer.
And alternatively, you can
just click in the document.
And if I just double click at
the very, very top, it will
automatically open the header.
And then I can decide what I
wish to put in to the header.
And for an example, I'm going
to insert the date and time.
So if I select the date and time
icon, I'm going to select which
format that I want it to display in
and I'll select the second one down.
So I select that one there.
And that will give me
the date in the header.
The beauty of using the headers and
footers is that when you make changes or
you move further down the page and the
document size increases, so if I scroll
down and just move on to another page.
As you can see, it's automatically
entered the date onto that page.
Similarly, if I wish to add page
numbers, I would just scroll
to the bottom of the document.
And again, I can go to the insert tab or
I can just double click right at the very
bottom of the document, which will open
the footer and then I can add page number.
So I select page number and then I would
obviously select the alignments, so do I
want align to the right, center or left?
And I want to go for the center.
Select OK.
And that will insert a page
number into the footer.
And as you can see, that is
carried through on every page.
You can access the headers and footers
at any time so I can click away from that
and then work on my document, perhaps
I wanted to make a change to the date
format so I could just double click back
into that, highlight the date format and
select a different way of displaying it.
Select OK.
And that will change that.
And again, if I wanted to change
how the footer or the page number
in the footer is displayed, l could
double-click in the footer, highlight
the number and select page number it
may be that I want to right align that.
Select OK and that will
automatically right align it.
You can also insert images and other
information into the header as required.